

#### **PROFILE**

Highly skilled Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience building quality software applications at scale. Strong communicator and problem-solver with a track record of delivering robust and extensible infrastructure. Experienced in working with complex federal, state, and agency regulations in financial and healthcare sectors.

#### CONTACT

#### PHONE:

(732)-682-0887

#### **WEBSITE:**

https://www.firas.casa

#### LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fsattar

#### **EMAIL**

firas.a.sattar@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

#### Languages:

Python, Java, C, C#, HTML/CSS

### AI/Computer Vision:

fastai, opencv, Tesseract, Jupyter, numpy, pandas, MATLAB

#### Database:

OracleDB, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch

#### Cloud/Infrastructure:

Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, AWS, GCC

#### **HOBBIES**

Visual art (painting, drawing, ceramics), recording music (guitar, piano, singing), hiking, nature, travel

# FIRAS SATTAR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **EDUCATION**

**Rutgers University – New Brunswick, School of Arts and Sciences**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – Mathematics Minor

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Sept. 2012 - May 2016

#### Fin3 Technologies Inc., Software Engineer

March 2022 - July 2022

Fin3 is a startup focused on connecting banking cores with blockchains. Their Blockchain Interface System (BIS) allows customers to seamlessly convert traditional currency to tokenized stablecoin for transacting on the blockchain.

- Contributed to backend integration of core BIS software with blockchains like Stellar and Provenance, collaborating with third-party development teams to meet stakeholder requirements.
- Built a robust framework for custodial wallet management with secure key generation and rotation using Fortanix API.
- Automated publishing of code packages and other CI/CD processes using GitHub Actions scripts.

#### IBIS Inc. - EICON, Software Engineer

November 2017 - March 2022

IBIS specializes in medical imaging solutions, primarily in the regulated Clinical Research space. Using a robust clinical data management platform, IBIS provides high-end data management solutions to the life sciences/healthcare communities.

- Developed an AI and computer vision-based image anonymizer to automate redaction of sensitive information from medical imaging data, addressing privacy requirements for data used in research.
- Conducted research and development on DICOM de-identification, resulting in securing a \$400,000 grant. (SBIR 411 and 427)
- Created validated, HIPAA-compliant Python Docker service for secure transmission of medical imaging data.
- Developed a configurable DICOM metadata extraction tool utilizing Elasticsearch to meet sub-second performance requirements for enterprise Pharma customers.
- Participated in formal validation of software platform by conducting system testing leading to a successful audit. (21CFR Part 11)

## **IDT Corporation (Products and Services Platform), Software Engineer**July 2016 – November 2017

The Products and Services Platform (PSP) is responsible for 47% of IDT revenue. As a member of the development team supporting PSP:

- Created configurable call simulators for testing flagship calling app Boss Revolution Mobile (BR Mobile).
- Developed a Java application to assess customer call, data, and SMS eligibility based on standing and initiate account status changes.
- Built a front-end account management application (WebAdmin) using React.js.

#### **IDT Corporation, Software Engineering Intern**

Summer 2014, Summer 2015

- Developed an Oracle database-querying application in Python for monitoring telecom network traffic and generating alerts based on traffic conditions.
- Wrote Python scripts to search Call Detail Records on Unix-based systems using regex-matching.